本字幕首发于字幕组网站
www.ZiMuZu.tv 欢迎交流
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
翻译： 潇湘月影 香茗小焙 Reginamoon 鱼小姐
翻译：王大可 杨一勾 某羽 小饭
时间轴：youliss  今     校对：油炸电风扇   潇湘月影
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第五季   第五集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
我听说你今天上午要给接替我的人面试
I hear you're interviewing replacements this morning.
没错
I am.
-你工作做得好吗  -我是出色
- You good at what you do? - I'm great at what I do.
那你明天开始上班
Then you start tomorrow.
我想提议
I'd like to propose a change
对当前的薪酬计算方法进行调整
to the current compensation formula.
如果我们投票的话
How many partners do you have in your pocket
你能调动多少合伙人支持
if we put your proposal to a vote?
45%
I can get 45%.
我能帮你通过投票
I'm gonna get you the difference.
这是哈维最近三个案子的收益表
This is Harvey's last three income statements,
我发现它们被放在复印机里
and I found them sitting in the copy machine.
是你主动为我工作的  你该作出决定了
You came to work for me, so now it's time for you to decide.
你到底要不要站在我这边
Are you with me or not?
我刚刚要求进行投票
I just called for a vote,
希望你有存钱的习惯
and I hope you've been saving your money,
因为你那钱多事少的工作马上就要没了
because your gravy train's about to leave the station.
-我打911  -这不是心脏病突发
- Okay, I'm dialing 911. - It's not a heart attack.
这是恐慌症
It's a panic attack.
记得我说过  我会找你
Remember when I said if I wanted you to make up
弥补薪金投票的事情吗
for the compensation vote I would come to you directly?
现在我来了
Well, now I am.
我们来回顾一下你的光荣历史
Well, let's take a look at your resume.
篡改证词  勒索  贿赂
Witness tampering, extortion, bribery.
伪造证据很适合你
Forgery fits right in.
我还真调查过你妈妈
I actually looked into your mommy,
结果发现  你跟爸爸待在家里时
And it turns out that the whole time
你妈妈在外面搞...
you were home with daddy, mommy was out banging--
哈维  最近还好吗
Hey, harv. How's it going?
你能确定那男人
You're absolutely certain the man
就是这个叫特拉维斯・坦纳的
was this Travis Tanner person?
是的
Yes.
你也很确定那女人不是唐娜
And yet you're just as certain the woman wasn't Donna?
我说过了
That's what I said.
我知道  但你没说她是谁
I know that, but you haven't said who she was.
你为什么那样看着我
Why are you looking at me like that?
你知道为什么
You know why.
我不知道她是谁
I don't know who she was.
好吧  这么说吧
Okay, then let's try this.
你觉得为什么特拉维斯・坦纳
Why do you think Travis Tanner all of a sudden
会突然跑进你的潜意识里
popped into your subconscious?
因为我现在正处理的案子对方是他
Because I'm in the middle of a case against him.
既然你不愿意再聊你的梦了
Well, since you don't want to talk about the dream anymore,
不如聊聊这个案子
why don't we talk about the case?
一点都不吓人
That's not creepy at all.
我就想知道你为什么换发型
I was just wondering why you changed your hair.
我一直就这发型啊
Hair's the same as it's always been.
你想看着老一点  还是年轻点
You trying to look older? Younger?
不管想怎么样  都不成功
Whatever it is, it isn't working.
你说完了吗  我在努力
Are you finished? 'Cause I'm actually trying
赶计费工时呢
to catch up on some billables here.
我只是顺路过来给你个小礼物
Hey, I just stopped by to give you a little gift
祝贺你赢下赞恩的案子的
for winning the Zane case.
礼物  你从没在案子结束后给过我礼物
A gift? You've never given me a gift after a case.
不是这样的
That's not true.
仔细想想  你都从没恭喜过我
Come to think of it, you've never even congratulated me,
也就是说  你来的真正目的是
which means you're actually here because,
天呐  你想我了
oh, my god, you miss me.
-我确实...没想你  -你还好吗
- I did...not miss you. - Are you okay?
你今晚想过来我家吗
Do you want to come over tonight?
我们可以看《西雅图夜未眠》
We can watch ?Sleepless in Seattle.
-你想不想要礼物了  -什么礼物
- Do you want your gift or not? - That's it?
这礼物看起来像文件夹
My gift looks a lot like a folder.
是个案子
It's a case.
咱俩一起绝杀特拉维斯・坦纳
You and me killing it against Travis Tanner.
-跟以前一样  -一样
- Just like old times? - Just like old times.
-那我们还等什么呢  -不等什么
- Well, what are we waiting for? - Nothing.
他正在来提和解协议的路上
He's on his way over with a settlement offer right now.
和解  听着不像坦纳的风格
Settlement? That doesn't sound like Tanner.
-正是他的风格  -怎么会
- Sounds exactly like Tanner. - How's that?
他已经开始挥白旗了
He's starting off waving a white flag.
他只是在明修栈道
Yeah, he's doing it just to go behind our backs
背地想暗渡陈仓
so he can attack our flank.
你意思说我们得小心提防
So you're saying we need to watch our flank.
不  我说咱们得渡他的陈仓
No, I'm saying we need to attack his.
-怎么了  -我要说实话
- What? - I'm just gonna say it.
我们每次对上坦纳都不轻松
Every time we go up against Tanner, it gets brutal.
你那天刚恐慌症发作过
You just had a panic attack the other day,
你真的确定现在要这么做吗
so are you sure this is really what you need right now?
我现在正需要这么做
It's exactly what I need right now.
我们去灭掉他
Let's go get him.
路易  这是什么
Louis? What's this?
那代表了我的谢意
That is a token of my appreciation.
你让我相信哈维不会伤害埃斯特  你是对的
You told me to trust Harvey with Esther and you were right.
现在我跟哈维和好了
Now Harvey and I are good.
你要想每次我说对
Well, if you're gonna give me a gift
都给我份礼物的话
every time I turn out to be right,
我就得需要一个大点的公寓了
then I'm gonna need a bigger apartment.
不是每次都有  但这次必须给
Well, not every time, but this time.
你的泥浴俱乐部  我要去做泥浴
Your mud club. I'm going mudding?
其实更棒
Even better.
我们要一起去做泥浴
We are going mudding.
路易  我不知道要说什么
Wow, Louis. I don't know what to say.
这...
This is, um....
-很棒  -不太合适
- Wonderful? - Inappropriate.
拜托  唐娜
Oh, come on, Donna.
我觉得你没理解
I don't think you understand.
想象一下
Picture this.
你和我  并排躺着  全裸
You and me, side by side, completely naked,
我们的身体埋在大地母亲的汁液之下
our bodies covered in the juices of mother earth.
现在我理解它完全是合适的
Oh, yeah, now I can see exactly how it's totally appropriate.
没错
Exactly.
唐娜  相信我
And Donna, trust me.
你第一次踏入我的泥浆的温暖怀抱时
When you dip your virgin toe in the deep warmth of my mud,
会脱胎换骨
you're never gonna be the same again.
杰西卡  我们有问题了
Jessica, we have a problem.
我看了律所章程
I went through the bylaws.
结果发现我们新的薪酬结构
Turns out the new compensation structure is in violation
违反了C35节
of subsection C35.
所以投票本身就是无意义的
So the vote in itself is moot.
你是说我们得改回
So you're saying we're going back
旧的薪资结构去
to the old compensation structure?
不是我说的  是条款C35说的
No, I'm not saying that. Subsection C35 is saying that.
只有一个问题
There's only one problem.
条款C35  24小时前还不存在呢
Subsection C35 didn't exist 24 hours ago.
-杰西卡  -别废话了  路易
- Jessica-- - Cut the shit, Louis.
告诉我你到底想干嘛
Tell me what this is really about.
我想和哈维重归于好
It's about me trying to make things right with Harvey.
我对此完全没意见
And I have no problem with that.
但我还需要你弥补咱俩的关系
But I also need you to make things right with me.
什么意思
What are you talking about?
这个投票是对我权威的一次冲击
That vote was an assault on my power.
我要让这事昏过去
I sneak this by,
我就拿不回我的权威了
I don't get my power back.
那会让我沦落到你和杰克的境地
It just makes me the same as you and Jack.
所以你不能像你俩当初
So you're not going to undo this thing
用见不得人的手段通过投票那样
the same shady way that the two of you
偷偷摸摸地让决议失效
passed it in the first place.
杰西卡  我说了
Jessica, I told you,
我把哈维的薪金表留在复印机里
leaving Harvey's compensation in the copier
是个意外
was an accident.
圣诞老人还从烟囱里爬下来
And a man named Santa Claus climbs down chimneys
把礼物送到圣诞树下呢
and leaves presents under trees.
好吧  行了  我明白了
Okay, fine, I get it.
你不相信我
You don't believe me.
但我要如何说服那些高级合伙人
But how the hell am I supposed to convince the senior partners
从自己的口袋里掏钱出来呢
to take money out of their own pockets?
那就是你的问题了
That's your problem.
你想要撤销那条决议  那就发起投票吧
You want to reverse that policy, bring it up for a vote.
爷们点
Like a man.
皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特律所
打扰了  小老虎
Excuse me, tiger.
你不想要在接待处登记一下吗
Don't you want to check in at reception?
-我知道我要去哪里  -你不知道
- Oh, I know where I'm going. - No, you don't.
我猜你知道我是谁  但你不是唐娜
Yeah, I'd say you know who I am, but you're not Donna.
我的确不是  但我确实知道你是谁
No, I'm not. But I do know who you are.
那你也知道我是来见谁的了
Well, then you know who I'm here to see.
我还知道你第一次来这里的时候
I also know that the very first time you ever came here,
直接穿过保安绕过唐娜
you walked right past security and by Donna.
但就像你说的  我不是唐娜
But like you just said, I'm not Donna.
我喜欢你  你今天顶她班吗
I like you. You filling in for the day?
不关你的事
None of your business.
我是说  等红发小姐回来后
Hey, I'm just saying, when red gets back,
也许你会愿意来替我工作
maybe you want to come work for me.
我已经有工作了
I already have a job.
如今的任务就是把您这尊大神
And right now it's getting your sorry ass
请到会议室去
into the conference room.
那你要怎么办
So what are you gonna do?
只有一个办法了
The only thing I can do.
让哈维求我另外一件事吧
Get Harvey to ask me for something else.
不行  不可能
No, not an option.
唐娜  我搞定这个的唯一办法
Donna, the only way I can get this done
就是让杰克・索罗夫帮忙
is with Jack Soloff's help,
但他是没可能会撤销那个
and there is no way that he's gonna reverse
让他一战成名的提案的
the very same proposal that put him on the map.
我来告诉你哈维会怎么做
I'll tell you what Harvey would do.
我不在乎哈维会怎么做
I don't care what Harvey would do,
因为我做不成哈维会做的事
Because I cannot do what Harvey would do.
哈维会怎么做
What would Harvey do?
他会想办法让杰克觉得值得这么做
He'd find a way to make it worth Jack's while.
让瑞秋给我一份下个月会进行的
Get Rachel to get me a list of every major corporate merger
重大合并项目列表
pending in the next month.
这才是我效力的路易
There is the Louis I came to work for.
说得没错  我来了  我要搞定这件事
You are right. Here I am. And I'm gonna get it done.
而当我搞定以后
And when I do,
你和我就要共享一次漫长的泥浴
you and I are going for a long, slow mud.
不  我不去
No, we're not.
假如你是来检查空气的
If you're here to check the air,
38楼就像桑拿房一样
it's like a sauna on the 38th floor.
很高兴见到你  哈维
Good to see you, Harvey.
很开心能看到有些人永远不会变
Nice to know some people never change.
没有风趣幽默的反驳吗  你怎么了
No witty rejoinder? What's going on?
老了力不从心了吗
You slowing down in your old age?
也可能是睾丸酮低
Could be low T.
睾丸酮低直接影响性生活
我可以和你们扯一天的淡
And I could talk shit with you guys all day,
但我来这里是因为我关心我的客户
but I'm here because I care about my client.
也许你的客户就不该试图
Well, then maybe your client shouldn't have tried
用偷来的知识产权开公司
to launch a company with stolen IP.
那知识产权不是偷的
That IP wasn't stolen.
是阿丽莎自己创造的
Alyssa created it herself.
是不是她创造的不重要
It doesn't matter whether she created it or not.
她签署了协议说所有权在我们
She signed a contract that says we own it,
而且存在她最后一天上班后带回家的
and it was on our laptop that she took home
我们的笔记本电脑上
on her last day.
我们不会让你带着我们的东西走出那扇门的
And we're not letting you walk out the door with our property.
好吧  我告诉过你了这和我无关
Okay, I told you this isn't about me.
行了  你想要什么  坦纳
Okay, what do you want, Tanner?
我想要提供一份协议
I want to make an offer.
阿丽莎愿意给你们15%的股权
Alyssa is willing to give you a 15% stake
请你们放手
to drop this whole thing.
就算她全给我们也没用
She could make it 100% for all I care.
-我们不和解  -你们不用和解
- We're not settling. - You don't have to settle,
但你确实得把那份提议给你们的客户看
but you do have to present that offer to your client
你清楚的
and you know it.
我会的  只不过需要先把它从屁话
I will, I just need to get it translated
翻译成英语
from bullshit to English.
哈维  看着我  那份提议很合理
Harvey, look at me. That's a fair offer.
不  你看着我  告诉我
No, you look at me and tell me
你没有在我们背后耍花招
and tell me you're not doing something behind our backs right now.
-我没有  -但是我们有
- I'm not. - Well, we are.
你的秘书说在这次会议前
Your secretary said you wouldn't file a TRO
你是不会申请临时禁制令的
until after this meeting.
我们是没有
Oh, we didn't.
但是我们发现兰小姐欠了一大笔债
Turns out that Miss Lang has some outstanding debts,
所以我们就去把它们买了下来
so we just went ahead and bought those up
取得了她财产的扣押权
and put a lien on her property.
我们说话这会儿警察正在封她办公室
The sheriff's padlocking her offices as we speak.
哈维  别这么做  你会后悔的
Harvey, don't do this. You'll be sorry.
这话留着跟法官说去吧
Tell that to the judge.
明天一早我们就去申请临时禁制令
We're filing that TRO in the morning.
我告诉你  我不是从前的我了
I'm telling you, I'm not the guy I used to be,
但假如你扇我一巴掌
but if you hit me,
我可不会把另半边脸也凑过去给你打
I'm not turning the other cheek.
我会还手的
You're gonna get hit back.
你为什么这么高兴
What are you so happy about?
我说了  这正是我需要的
I told you, it's exactly what I needed.
你和这个人针锋相对多少次了
You've gone up against this man how many times?
多到足够知道他是个垃圾
Enough to know that he's a piece of shit
为了赢会不惜牺牲所有底线
that'll cross whatever line it takes to win.
我听过的全是你牺牲的底线
All I've heard so far is the line that you crossed.
听着  你也许懂得人情世故
Listen, you may understand some things about people,
但你不懂我做的事
but you don't understand what I do.
在我听来  你做的事就是
Well, it sounds to me like what you did was attack a man
攻击一个已经投降的人
that was waving a white flag.
你刚才在听我说话吗
Were you listening?
他不是投降  是在设局陷害我们
He wasn't waving a white flag, he was setting us up.
你怎么能如此肯定呢
How can you be so sure?
因为我了解坦纳
Because I know Tanner.
如果你这么清楚他的能力
Okay, well, if you know so well what he was capable of,
为什么还要故意和他作对
why was it such a good idea to pick a fight with him?
因为这就是我的风格
Because it's what I do.
也许是时候考虑改变一下你的行事风格了
Well, maybe it's time to consider changing what you do.
好吧  那这样
Okay, here we go.
金坦公司和猎户制药怎么样
What about Gentech and Orion pharmaceuticals?
大并购  胜诉提成还有大赢面
Monster merger, contingent fee, and huge upside.
但奎瓦施在律师团队中
And Cravath is listed as the attorney of record,
所以如果他们退出  整个事就暴露了
which means if they swap out, it blows the whole thing up.
这个是最后一个了
Okay, well, that's the last one.
该死
Shit.
这个一直都在这里
Wait, this has been here the whole time.
约翰・德摩尔怎么样
What about John Dellmore?
他们要和阿尔金金融合并
They're merging with Arkin financial.
还没公布  就是在等着我们
Haven't been announced yet, it's just sitting there
-去收割啊  -不可能
- ripe for the taking. - No, not gonna happen.
德摩尔和哈蒙舒普合作几十年了
Dellmore's been with Harmon and Shupe for decades.
那又怎样  哈蒙舒普是个三流律所
So what? Harmon and Shupe is a third-tier law firm
舒普就是个笑话
And Shupe is a joke.
她也是约翰・德摩尔的妻子
She's also John Dellmore's wife.
也许我们能说服德摩尔
Well, so then maybe we can convince Dellmore
他妻子是个荡妇
that his wife is a trollop.
-路易  -他妈的
- Louis! - God damn it!
到底怎么了
What is going on?
我得让杰克・索罗夫推翻之前的薪金方案投票
I need Jack Soloff to overturn the compensation vote,
唯一的方法就是找到
and the only way for me to do that is to bring in
一个大额胜诉提成客户
a big contingent client.
然后和他分享收益
And share the money with him.
正是  但这些客户都没用
Exactly! And none of these people are it.
好吧
Okay.
等等  你去哪
Wait, where are you going?
就像你说的  这些客户都没用
Like you said, none of these people are it.
很晚了  我们都累了
It's late, we're both exhausted,
我明早还有个考试
and I've got a test in the morning.
瑞秋  拜托了
Rachel, please.
路易  对不起
Louis, I'm sorry.
我们明早再处理这件事  我保证
We'll work on it tomorrow morning, I promise.
瑞秋
Rach--
先生们  我很不喜欢没有充分理由发临时禁止令
Gentlemen, I don't like granting TROs without a good reason.
我们有充分理由  法官大人
We have a good reason, Your Honor.
它叫做合同
It's called a contract.
这份合同明确说明阿丽莎・兰
A contract that explicitly states that any product
在任职期间开发的任何产品
Alyssa Lang developed during her employment
都属于我的客户
is the property of our client.
很遗憾那份合同不可执行
Unfortunately that contract is unenforceable.
合同可执行  除非我今早是在俄罗斯醒来的
It is unless I woke up in Russia this morning.
法官大人  我这里有一份
Your honor, I have here a copy
阿丽莎・兰出生证明的副本
of Alyssa Lang's birth certificate.
她也许确实签了那份合同
She may have signed that contract,
但合同无效  因为她当时只有16岁
but it isn't binding because she was only 16 at the time.
什么
What?
法官大人  我了解这个人
Your honor, I know this man,
那份文件很可能来源非法
and that document could have come from anywhere.
文件已经经过匡提科的实验室证实
Get it verified by the labs at Quantico.
这份文件能证明阿丽莎・兰
All it's gonna prove is that Alyssa Lang
当时没有权利能力签署这份文件
had no legal capacity to sign.
她签署的时候多大并不重要
It doesn't matter how old she was when she signed it.
那是十年前的事情了
It was ten years ago.
自那之后的每张支票她都兑现了
She's cashed every paycheck she got since.
这可以作为你的庭审申辩
And you can argue that at trial,
但我们立法保护未成年人是有原因的
but we have laws protecting minors for a reason,
我不会签发禁令的
and I'm not granting a TRO.
还有一件事  法官大人
And one more thing, Your Honor.
我们已经全额支付  还清了她的债务
We have payment in full, discharging her debt,
在此要求她的公司恢复正常运营
and are requesting her doors be reopened.
这不是我们今天要讨论的事
That has nothing to do with why we're here.
留到庭审再说吧  斯佩克特先生  该吃饭了
Save it for trial, Mr. Specter. It's lunch.
我饿了  今天之内解除封锁
I'm hungry, and those padlocks are coming off today.
刚才是怎么回事
What the hell was that?
是你脸撞到拳击台地面的声音
That was the sound of your face hitting the canvas.
我建议你待着别起来了
I suggest you stay down.
我哪都不待  你这个混蛋
I'm not staying anywhere, you son of a bitch.
-你说什么  -你听到了
- Excuse me? - You heard me.
你的客户当时只有16岁
Your client was 16 years old
但你在洗心革面的说辞里
and you conveniently left that out
故意没提这件事
of your changed man speech.
我没告诉你是因为我知道
I didn't tell you about her because I knew
我说什么你都听不进去
you wouldn't listen to a thing I said
我给出了合理的条件
after I offered you a fair deal
可你让我滚
and you told me to go to hell.
瞎说  你不跟我们说是因为
Bullshit. You didn't tell us because
你想在法庭上搞突然袭击
you wanted to blindside us in court.
你才是那个在我伸出橄榄枝时
Hey, you're the one who turned out the lights out on Alyssa's business
非要针对阿丽莎的人
while I was extending an olive branch.
还是瞎说
Bullshit again.
我们都知道那个和解条件
We both know that settlement offer
只是为了让我们分心
was nothing but a distraction.
你想要分心吗
You want a distraction?
这是一份阿丽莎・兰
That is a draft of Alyssa Lang's
投诉你的客户性骚扰的草稿
sexual harassment complaint against your client.
因为我们开了条件  所以它还没有分你们的心
As far as our offer goes, it wasn't a distraction
因为我们还没有提交投诉
because we haven't filed that yet
我们的条件也依旧有效
and our offer's still on the table.
我建议你接受
I advise you to take it.
你不相信性骚扰的指控吗
You didn't believe the sexual harassment allegation?
-绝不相信  -为什么
- Not a chance. - Why not?
首先  这是坦纳说的
Well, for starters, it came out of Tanner's mouth.
而且我了解蒂姆・彼得罗夫  他没有出轨
And I know Tim Petroff, and he didn't cheat on his wife.
你为此很生气
And you're angry at him for that?
我当然生气了
You're damn right I am!
有些事情是不可以做的
There are some things you just don't do.
比如说谎吗
Like lie?
比如威胁要破坏人家的家庭
Like threaten to rip a man's family apart.
怎么了
What?
我只是觉得  你一个没结过婚的单身人士
I just find it interesting that you talk about family
把家庭说的那么神圣  很有趣
as if it were sacred, yet you've never married.
你从来没有过属于自己的家
You've never had a family of your own.
在这里我既没有看到通心粉画
I don't see any macaroni paintings
也没看到学校的相片
or school pictures in here either.
我的私人生活并不是今天的主题
And my personal life is not the topic here.
我们不如回到原本的主题
So why don't we get back to what is?
如果说跟坦纳开战真的是个好主意的话
If it was such a good idea to pick a fight with Tanner,
那你为什么会对这些你明知他会做的事情
why were you so angry at him for doing exactly
而感到生气呢
what you knew he would do?
你是医生  你告诉我
You're the doctor. You tell me.
好吧  可能因为把气撒在某个人的身上
Okay, maybe because getting angry at someone
是一个逃避自身麻烦的方法
is a way to avoid facing what's going on with yourself.
你回来了  真是太好了
Oh, good, you're back.
你在这里  肯定是有什么不好了
Can't be good if you're out here.
我不想让你毫无防备撞进去  你办公室里有...
Oh, I didn't want you to get ambushed. There's a--
贝塔软件的蒂姆・彼得罗夫
Tim Petroff of Betasoft in my office.
他已经在你的地毯上磨了半小时了
He's been wearing out your carpet for half an hour.
坦纳肯定已经把那份投诉给他了
Tanner must have sent him a copy of the complaint.
如果你指的是他手里攥的那张纸的话  是的
If you mean that paper balled up in his fist, I'd say he did.
多谢提醒  格蕾琴
Thanks for the heads-up, Gretchen.
蒂姆  在你开口之前
Tim, before you say anything--
性骚扰  这是什么鬼
Sexual harassment? What the hell is this?
这只是草稿  还没提交
It's only a draft. It hasn't been filed yet.
这话也算安慰吗
And that's supposed to make me feel better?
这根本就是谎言
It's a goddamn lie.
我连跟性骚扰有半点关系的事都没干过
I have never done anything remotely resembling harassing anyone.
-蒂姆  冷静点  -我才不要冷静
- Tim, calm down. - I'm not going to calm down.
这根本就是在曲解我的人格
This is a complete twisting of who I am.
我要这个女人身败名裂
I want this woman destroyed.
不是她干的  是她的律师
It's not her. It's her lawyer.
我不管
I don't care who it is.
我是有家室的人  我不想再看到这个
I have a wife and children, and I want this thing gone.
那你就应该了解下你桌上还有份和解协议
Then you should know there's a settlement on the table.
迈克  现在不是时候
Mike! Not now.
什么和解协议
What settlement?
她公司15%的股份
A 15% stake in her venture.
你疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
你觉得我会向这些靠敲诈勒索的人妥协吗
You think I'm gonna settle with these people based on blackmail?
没人要妥协
No one's settling.
是的  你说对了  没人妥协
Yeah, you're damn right no one's settling.
现在拿着你挣的钱  给我搞定这女人
Now earn your money and blow this woman out of the water.
你听到他说的了
You heard him.
找准机会把她彻底击倒  让她永无翻身之日
Figure out a way to put the screws to her once and for all.
哈维
Harvey.
我也不想再听到任何关于我心理状态的废话了
And I don't want to hear any shit about my state of mind.
我也并不打算说什么
I'm not gonna say anything about that,
但我要说的是  既然坦纳愿意让她这么做
but what I will say is that if Tanner's willing to make her do this,
怎么能保证他不会让她做
what's to say he's not willing to make her
更过分的事呢
do something worse?
你想做什么  迈克  你想让步吗
What do you want to do, Mike? You want to back down?
不  我想让坦纳被炒
No, I want to get Tanner fired.
可是我们跟她对话是违法的
It's not legal for us to talk to her.
可偶遇不违法啊
There's no law against me running into her by accident.
瑞秋  你在这里干嘛
Rachel, what are you doing here?
我到处在找你
I've been looking all over for you.
你意思不是  瑞秋  你考试怎么样吗
Don't you mean, "Hey, Rachel, how did your test go?"
我不在乎你考试考得怎么样
I don't care how your test went.
我需要你给我找到所有能找到的关于
I just need you to get me everything you can
约翰・德摩尔的资料
on John Dellmore.
路易  我们已经讨论过了
Louis, we've already been over this.
他的律师就是他老婆  你签不了他的
His lawyer's his wife. You're never gonna sign him.
那就是了  我不用真的签了他
Well, that's just it. I don't need to sign him.
我只要假装签了他就行
I only need to pretend to sign him.
这真是个坏主意
Okay. That's a bad idea.
不  才不是
No, it's not.
如果杰克以为我签到了德摩尔
If Jack thinks I signed Dellmore,
然后我告诉他我会分他一杯羹
and I tell him I'll give him a piece,
他知道这是一大笔钱
he'll know it's worth a fortune to him
然后他就会推翻投票了
and he'll overturn the vote.
那当他发现整件事都是个谎言的时候
And what are you gonna do when he finds out
你怎么办
the whole thing was a lie?
不会的  我会编几个悲伤感人的小故事
He won't. I'll make up some sob story
就讲德摩尔跟他老婆又和好了
about how Dellmore made up with his wife
我们要重振旗鼓  择日再战
and we'll live to fight another day.
他死都不会信的好吗
He's never gonna believe that.
瑞秋  换作是卡特里娜
Rachel, Katrina would have been
她从一开始就会答应
on board with this from day one.
好吧  路易  我很抱歉
Okay, Louis, I'm sorry.
我不是想泼你冷水
I am not trying to rain on your parade,
但一旦杰克发现了  他会恨你一辈子的
but when Jack finds out, he's going to hate you forever.
可是  我答应过哈维了
Well, I made a promise to Harvey.
如果让我在杰克恨我和
And if it's a choice between Jack hating me
和违背诺言之间选择
and breaking that promise,
那么我永远会选哈维
I'm picking Harvey every single time.
你到底需要什么
What exactly do you need?
我需要办法去晃花约翰・德摩尔的眼
I need a way to dazzle the shit out of John Dellmore.
谢谢
Thank you.
我不懂了  有人替我付过账了
I don't understand. My bill's been paid?
-是的先生  已经付过了  -谁付的
- Yes, sir, it has. - By who?
我付的
Uh, by me.
请问你是谁
And who exactly are you?
我是路易・利特
I'm Louis Litt.
而且我不仅替你结了帐
And not only did I pay for your check,
还给你带来了另一张支票
I also brought you another one.
你要给我的慈善基金捐5万块
You're donating $50,000 to my charity.
是的
Yes.
为什么
Why would you want to--
虽然看起来不像  但我也曾经无家可归
Because it may not look like it, but I was homeless.
有两年的时间都露宿街头
I spent two years on the streets,
要不是有您的机构帮忙
and had it not been for your family's organization,
我就不会有今天的成就
I would not be the man I am today.
我能做什么来感谢您吗
Is there anything I can do to thank you?
继续做您现在做的事就好了
Just keep doing what you're doing.
先生  你是个真正的美国英雄
You, sir, are a true American hero.
-谢谢你  -谢谢你
- Thank you. - Thank you.
太好了你在这儿
Oh, good, you're here.
刚是什么
What the hell was that?
是约翰・德摩尔
That was John Dellmore.
我知道他是谁
Yeah, I know who it is.
他抱你干嘛
Why was he giving you a hug?
因为我刚说服他  让咱俩处理他的并购案
Because I just convinced him to let us handle his merger.
你叫我过来跟这事有关系吗
Does that have something to do with why we're here?
我们就是为这个来的
It's got everything to do with why we're here,
因为我知道你永远不会相信
because I knew that you would never believe
我能拿下德摩尔这个客户
that I could close Dellmore.
没错
You're right.
如果不是亲眼所见  我是不会相信的
If I hadn't seen it myself, I never would have believed it.
为什么  因为我是个书呆子律师吗
And why is that? Because I'm a grinder?
是这样  杰克
Here's the thing, Jack.
你对付哈维时
When you took on Harvey,
你让书呆子律师站在了天才律师的对立面
you pitted the grinders against the rainmakers,
这招不错
and that was a good move,
但如果你想更进一步
But you want to move to the next level?
我们必须既赚工时也赚分成
We need to be both grinders and rainmakers.
你明白我的意思吗
Do you understand what I'm saying?
你是什么意思
What are you saying?
我是说我们必须
I'm saying that we need to revisit
重新制定薪金协议
the compensation agreement.
没门  我为什么要这么做
No way. Why would I do that?
因为要是我们接手这个客户
Because when we get this business,
我们就能赚一大笔钱
it will be worth a fortune to us.
-"我们"  -对  我们  杰克
- "Us"? - Yes, us, Jack.
如果你支持我
If you are with me on this,
我就把我赚的分你一半
I will give you 50 cents to every dollar that I make.
好  就这么定了
Yeah. Let's get this done.
小心  很烫的
Careful, it's really hot.
曾经有个女人因为被烫伤  起诉了麦当劳呢
A woman once sued McDonald's for getting burned.
不过我想你也可以假装被烫伤
Although I guess you could just say you got burned
然后起诉他们
and sue them anyway.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是谁不重要  重要的是我为谁工作
Doesn't matter who I am. It matters who I work for.
蒂姆・彼得罗夫
Tim Petroff.
你不能跟我说话
You can't talk to me.
我只是在调咖啡
I'm just fixing my coffee.
你想走随便你  但在你离开之前
You want to walk away, walk away, but before you do,
我要跟空气说
I'm gonna say to nobody in particular
你该炒了你的律师
that you should fire your lawyer.
我不会炒任何人
I'm not firing anybody.
那你该知道
Well, then you should also know that
诬告别人性骚扰
falsely accusing someone
可是犯罪
of sexual harassment is a criminal offense,
不管特拉维斯・坦纳跟你说了什么
and no matter what Travis Tanner has told you
说服你能够脱罪  脱不了的
to convince you that you'll get away with it, you won't.
我的指控中
There's nothing in that complaint
没有一条是假的
that isn't factually correct.
你在歪曲事实  这可能毁了一个人的一生
You are twisting those facts and you could ruin a man's life,
你知道的
and you know it.
这和他对我做的有什么区别
Oh, and how is that different from what he's doing to me?
-区别大了  -是吗
- It's completely different. - Is it?
十年来我每周为他工作六十小时
I worked for that man 60 hours a week for 10 years,
现在我想自己开公司
and now that I want to start my own company,
他不仅想打垮我
he not only wants to crush me,
还告诉别人我剽窃了他的创意
but he told people I stole the idea.
如果这都不算毁了别人的一生
If that's not ruining a person's life,
我不知道怎样才算
then I don't know what is.
至于特拉维斯・坦纳
Oh, and as far as Travis Tanner goes,
性骚扰不是他的主意
sexual harassment wasn't his idea.
是我的
It was mine.
他想劝我别这么做
And when he tried to talk me out of it,
我告诉他要么听我的
I told him he could either get on board
要么我就另请律师
or watch me get another lawyer.
瑞秋・赞恩  你真是荣耀的存在
Rachel Zane, you glorious creature.
-荣耀  -没错  荣耀
- Glorious? - Yes, glorious.
你是天才
I mean, you were masterful.
慈善基金的事
The charity,
他独自在他喜欢的餐厅吃午餐的事
his lone lunches at his favorite restaurant,
还让杰克出现得恰到好处
having Jack show up at the perfect time.
你不只是优秀的律师
I mean, you are not only a brilliant attorney,
你简直是主心骨啊
you're the backbone of this entire--
路易  我不会跟你去洗泥浴的
Louis, I'm not going mudding with you.
该死  唐娜跟你说什么了
God damn it! What did Donna tell you?
她说如果事情顺利
She told me that if it went well,
你会过来邀请我洗泥浴庆祝
you would come in here trying to get a celebratory mud,
如果事情不顺利
and that if it didn't go well,
你会邀请我洗泥浴安慰你
you would try to get a sympathy mud.
等等  我能跟你洗安慰泥浴吗
Wait a second, I could have got a sympathy mud?
不  不行
No, you couldn't.
但好消息是  你在杰克那里达到了目的
But the good news is, you got what you wanted with Jack,
不仅如此  路易  你还真正地
and on top of that, Louis, you really made a difference
为流浪儿童的生活做出了巨大的贡献
in the lives of homeless children.
提醒我了  投票之后
Which reminds me. After the vote,
你帮我止付那张支票
I want you to put a stop payment on that check.
不  这也太卑鄙了
Okay, no--that is a despicable thing to do.
得了  所有声称用于做好事的慈善基金
Please, any charity claiming to do a good thing
明显都是骗人的  我才不上当呢
is clearly a scam. I won't have it.
你的意思是你很小气吧
So you mean you're cheap?
作为一个不肯
You know what, for someone
陪我洗安慰泥浴的人
who won't throw me a sympathy mud,
你评论太多了
you're very judgmental.
路易  有事吗
Louis. What can I do for you?
你可以给我你的代表权
You can give me your proxy.
为什么
Why would I do that?
你让我爷们儿一点
Because you asked me
就薪金问题发起投票
to bring the compensation issue up for a vote
我做了
like a man and I did.
杰克・索罗夫知道吗
And is Jack Soloff aware of this?
他不只知道  还要投赞成票呢
Not only aware of it, he's voting for it.
你是怎么说服他的
And however did you get him to do that?
这么说吧  你想让我按哈维的方法
Let's just say that you wanted me to do this
而不是我的方法了结这事
like Harvey would have and not like I would have,
但我做到了两全其美
but I did the best of both.
那么你可以代表我了
Then you have my proxy.
哈维  我跟阿丽莎・兰谈过了
Harvey, I talked to Alyssa Lang
有些事该让你知道
and there's something you should know.
让我猜猜  她眨着她的大眼睛
Let me guess, she batted her eyes,
给你讲了个悲伤的故事
told you a sob story,
现在你认为她是无辜的
and now you think she's some kind of innocent.
不  不是这样
No, I don't.
事实上  她告诉我
In fact, she told me that
性骚扰的主意是她想出来的
the sexual harassment idea was hers.
我有什么必要知道这些
And why do I need to know that?
我觉得我们应该考虑接受交易
I think we should consider taking the deal.
不行
Well, we're not gonna do that.
为什么
Why not?
首先  蒂姆是不可能
Because first of all, there's now way on earth
接受和解的
that Tim's gonna settle.
你可以说服他  你知道的
You could convince him and you know it.
其次  那样起诉不可能
And second of all, there's no way on earth
是她的主意
that that suit was her idea.
哈维  你当时不在场
Harvey, you weren't there, all right?
没错  可我不必在那就知道
Yeah, I didn't have to be there to know
如果坦纳一开始就能说服她做那种事
that if Tanner could convince her to do that bullshit in the first place,
他定也可以让她说那是她自己的注意
he could sure as hell get her to say it was her idea.
他不可能知道我会联系她
He couldn't have known that I was gonna contact her.
他可能  也那么做了
He could, and he did.
别再跟我提这事了
And I don't want to hear another word about it.
你千方百计去让她开掉他的时候
And while you were away trying to get her to cut him loose,
我在这里想办法如何
I was here trying to figure out how to do
按蒂姆说的干掉她
what Tim asked us to do and blow her away.
哈维  这可不是玩笑事
Harvey, this isn't a joke.
我没开玩笑
I'm not joking.
唯一能让坦纳退却的
The only way to get Tanner to back down
就是给他迎头一击
is to point a cannon in his face.
你这不是给他迎头一击
You're not pointing it in his face.
是对她  一旦你起诉
You're pointing it in hers, and once you put this in motion,
就不一定能再回头了
there's no guarantee that you're gonna be able to pull it back.
她在雇特拉维斯・坦纳之前
She should have thought of that before
就该想到
she hired Travis Tanner.
我先介绍一下这个提议
Listen, I'm gonna start by introducing the proposal,
然后你就接进来
then you chime in.
杰克  我给你50%德摩尔
Jack, I gave you 50% of Dellmore,
但得让我看起来是这案子的主导
but I need to be seen as leading the charge on this.
路易  我告诉其他合伙人
Louis, I got the partners in line
这是我的提议才让他们加入我们
by telling them it was my proposal.
好  那我做引入  说全力支持你
Okay, so I'll introduce you with my full support
然后你接着讲
and then you can just take it from there.
-好的  -对了  我们搞定这事
- Okay. - Oh, and by the way, when we win this thing,
或许你和我可以一起泡泥浴
maybe you and I can go mudding together.
我们先认真把会开完吧
Why don't we just focus on our meeting?
好
Right.
首先我想感谢大家出席本次会议
First of all, I would like to thank everyone for coming.
这次要讨论的是杰克和我
The issue at hand is a very important proposal
努力研究出的一个重要提议
that Jack and I have been working on.
我获得了哈维和杰西卡的代理权
I have both Harvey and Jessica's proxies.
我很高兴这个方案得到他俩的支持
And I am pleased to say this measure has their full support.
-杰克  -谢谢  路易
- Jack. - Thank you, Louis.
考虑到最近律所新的
In light of the impact of recent changes in the firm
薪酬结构变动带来的影响
resulting from the new compensation structure,
路易和我都坚定地认为
Louis and I strongly feel that there should be
未来一年不该再有新的变动
no new policy changes for the next 12 months.
什么
What?
正如路易所说  冠名合伙人都同意了
And as Louis just said, the name partners gave their blessing.
我们不如全体一致通过吧
So why don't we make it unanimous?
全都同意
All in favor?
看来提议被通过了
Motion seems to have passed.
下一个议程
Next order of business.
你刚才在搞什么鬼
What the hell did you just do?
我搞什么鬼  我只是保护自己的利益
What the hell did I do? I protected my own interests.
-我们谈好了的  -谈好了什么
- We had a deal! - We didn't have a thing.
你以为我会信餐厅那出约翰・德摩尔的戏吗
You think I bought that John Dellmore stunt at the restaurant?
你走到我桌边的时候我就看穿你了
I was on to you the second you walked over to my table.
我听你废话连篇
I let you give me that bullshit speech
书呆子律师和天才律师的话  只是为了
about grinders and rainmakers just so I could do
我能导演出刚才的好戏
what I just did.
好  我明白了
Okay, I get it.
你明确了态度  也建立了声望
You made your point, you made a name for yourself,
可是  杰克  你得推翻刚才的提议
but, Jack, you need to undo this.
你凭什么觉得我能够推翻
What makes you think I could have undone it
刚才的提议呢
in the first place?
他们投票同意那个提议
They voted for that proposal
是因为那增加了他们口袋里的钱
because it put more money in their pockets,
现在木已成舟
And now it's there to stay.
对了  如果你想约人泡泥浴
By the way, if you want to go mudding with someone,
为什么不找哈维・斯佩克特呢
why don't you ask Harvey Specter?
这件事用脚指头猜都知道
Because it doesn't take a genius to figure out
他才是让你干这个苦差事的
that he's the one that got you to carry his water
始作俑者
in the first place.
谢谢
Thanks.
我帮你叫了今日特选
I got you the special.
你说了不要腌菜吗
Did you say no pickles?
你没说不要腌菜啊
You didn't say no pickles.
我也没叫你帮我买午饭啊
I didn't say, "Order my lunch."
来告我呀
So sue me.
你把律师函发给坦纳了吗
You send the notification over to Tanner?
两小时前
Two hours ago.
那用不着很久了
Then it won't be long.
怎么了
What?
蒂姆・彼得罗夫来后我再没提过你的精神状态
I didn't say anything about your state of mind after Tim Petroff
因为那时我还不担心
because I wasn't worried about it then,
-但现在我担心了  -迈克
- but I am now. - Mike--
-如果失败了呢  -不会的
- What if it doesn't work? - It'll work.
-如果失败了呢  -也是坦纳的事
- And what if it doesn't? - Then it's on Tanner.
不  是你的事  我现在告诉你
No, it's on you, because I'm telling you right now,
坦纳没有操纵这件事
Tanner is not driving this thing.
说曹操曹操到啊
Well, speak of the devil.
你这个混帐
You son of a bitch.
你对我的委托人提起刑事诉讼
You filed criminal charges against my client?
你说的没错
You're damn right we did.
她伪造了一张驾照
She forged a fake driver's license
关联了她的W2报税表
and attached it to her w2.
-这可是十年的税收欺诈  -你这个混蛋
- That's ten years of tax fraud. - Oh, you piece of shit.
就算是你  这么做也太过分了
This is crossing the line even for you.
我怎么了
For me?
从我认识你的那天起  你的所作所为
Ever since the day I met you, all you've done is cross lines,
才真的过分  先是剥削癌症患者的钱
and it started with you ripping off cancer victims,
后来的事就更别提了
not to mention every other thing you've ever done.
我告诉过你  我不再是以前那个我了
Hey, I told you I am not that guy anymore.
没错  说完转头就拿狗屁性骚扰
Yeah, right before you tried to ruin my client's life
起诉我的委托人  想毁了他的生活
with some bullshit sexual harassment charge.
那是因为他断了我的委托人的生路
Right after he padlocked my client's livelihood.
没错  他是这么做了
Yeah, you're damn right he did!
-哈维  -每次你跟我对着干
- Harvey-- - Because if you're on a case against me,
伤害到我在乎的人
it's just a matter of time
就只是时间问题
until you eviscerate someone I care about.
伤害
Eviscerate?
如果我想伤害你在乎的人
If I was gonna eviscerate someone you cared about,
我只要点明
all I'd have to do is point out
为什么唐娜不再替你干活了
how Donna's no longer working for you.
离开这里  坦纳
Hey, get out of here, Tanner.
她现在替路易・利特做事
She's working for Louis Litt.
-你刚才跟我说什么  -你听得很清楚
- What did you just say to me? - You heard me.
然后就上去问她  "红发妞  怎么回事
And then I'd go up to her and say, "What happened, Red?
"是不是哈维厌倦和你上床了
"Did harvey get tired of banging you?
"还是他的功夫实在太差了  你抛弃了他
"Or was he such a lousy lay that you left him
"随便在街上找了一个男人  就像他妈妈
"for the guy down the road just like Harvey's mom
"对待他亲爱的老爹一样"
"did to dear, old dad?"
哈维  哈维  快住手
Harvey! Harvey! Stop!
坦纳  赶紧滚
Tanner, get out of here now!
滚
Go!
你就绝对肯定
You're absolutely convinced
坦纳说的不是实话吗
Tanner couldn't be telling the truth?
这有什么关系吗
What does it matter?
你很可能会毁掉这个女人的一生
Well, you could be ruining this woman's life.
那不是我的问题
That's not my problem.
所以你不相信给人第二次机会吗
So you don't believe in second chances?
我可没这么说
I didn't say that.
是没有  你只是说
No, you just said
一个你不信任的人发誓说他已经改过自新了
a man you didn't trust swore he changed.
然后你不仅没有给他第二次机会来证明这一点
And instead of giving him a chance to prove that,
还对他全面开战
you launched an all-out war.
你到底有没有在听我讲的故事
Were you listening to my goddamn story?
你没听到他说的话吗
Did you hear what he said?
那根本不是一个改过自新的人
That is not a man that's changed.
不  我说的是你的所作所为
No, I'm talking about what you did.
是你挑起了一场全面战争
You launched an all-out war.
我那样做是为了我的委托人
I did that for my client.
而且顺便告诉你
And for your information,
我给过很多人第二次机会
I've given plenty of people second chances.
-比如说谁  -比如  路易
- Like who? - Louis, for one.
迈克
Mike.
唐娜  斯科特
Donna, Scottie,
我弟弟  我...
My brother, my...
你的什么人
Your what?
我以为我们在谈这个案子
I thought we were talking about the case.
我们是从谈论你的梦开始的
We started by talking about your dream.
对  我因为这个案子才做的那个梦
Yeah, the one I had because of my case.
而你说你梦里的那个女人
Mm-hmm. And you said the woman in that dream
不是唐娜
wasn't Donna.
但这讲不通  因为那个男人是坦纳
But it doesn't add up, because the man was Tanner
而你刚刚告诉我你做梦那天
and you just told me what he said about her the same day
他是怎么说她的
that you had that dream.
好吧  我不在乎讲不讲得通
Yeah, well, I don't care if it doesn't add up
因为我说的是实话
because I'm telling the truth.
可你浑身上下都露出马脚说你在撒谎
And yet you have tells all over you that say otherwise.
那你根本不懂什么是马脚
Then you don't know what a tell is,
因为我从不露马脚
because I don't have any.
那好啊
All right.
我们来看看到底谁知道马脚是什么
We'll see who knows what a tell is.
你要和我打牌吗
You want to play poker with me?
是的
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
我要和你打牌
I'm gonna play poker with you.
等我把你的钱都赢光以后
And when I win, and you're out of money,
你要和我说实话
You're gonna tell me the truth.
那要是我把你的钱全赢光  我能得到什么
And what do I get when you're out of money?
无所谓  因为你不可能赢
It doesn't matter 'cause it's never gonna happen.
有件事我得和你谈谈
I need to talk to you about something.
-怎么了  -特拉维斯・坦纳刚给我打电话
- What's going on? - I just got a call from Travis Tanner.
想让我半个小时后和他见面
He wants me to meet him in half an hour.
这事你得告诉哈维
Well, you have to tell Harvey.
我给他留了两条信息了
I left him two messages.
他还没回复我  而就算他回我
He hasn't gotten back to me, but even if he does,
也肯定会告诉我不要去
he's gonna tell me not to go.
那就别去
Well, then don't go.
你不能背着哈维做事啊
You can't go behind Harvey's back.
这就是问题所在
That's the thing.
如果去见坦纳其实是在帮哈维呢
What if going to see Tanner is more like having Harvey's back?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我们这个案子对方的委托人
The client on the other side of our case
十年前做过一张假身份证明
made a fake ID ten years ago
结果现在哈维准备为此把她送进监狱
and now Harvey's ready to send her to prison for it,
而且他这样做完全是为了对付坦纳
and he's only doing it because of Tanner.
好吧  但那终归还应该由哈维来决定
Okay, but it's still Harvey's call.
如果他以现在的精神状态作出这个决定
And if he makes that call in his current state of mind,
他可能会后悔终身
he might regret it for the rest of his life.
你说他现在的精神状态是什么意思
What do you mean, his current state of mind?
几周前  我走进哈维的办公室
A couple of weeks ago, I walked into Harvey's office
他正恐慌症发作
and he was having a panic attack.
天呐
Oh, my God.
那个再加上昨天
And on top of that, yesterday,
他们两个大吵起来
the two of them got into a yelling match
最后发展到哈维给了坦纳一拳
that ended with Harvey punching Tanner.
好吧
Okay, look.
你需要做什么就去做吧
Do whatever you have to do.
帮助哈维
Have Harvey's back.
他在哪
Where is he?
-我不知道  -你不知道才有鬼了
- I don't know. - Bullshit, you don't know.
杰西卡  我发誓昨晚之后我再没见过他
Jessica, I swear I haven't seen him since last night.
那我需要知道  他是不是对我撒谎了
Then I need to know, did he lie to me?
唐娜  我一直都信任你
Donna... I've always trusted you.
现在我需要你信任我
Now I need you to trust me.
他是不是做了什么见不得人的勾当去骗杰克
Did he do some underhanded shit to fool Jack
结果自食其果了
and it backfired?
是的
Yes.
你说的一点不差
That's exactly what he did.
那就找到他
Then find him.
让他来见我
And tell him to come see me.
我还能说什么  三张K一对六
What can I say? Kings full of 6s.
好吧  哈维  你赢了
All right, Harvey, you won.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
我就不能先洋洋得意一会儿吗
Can't I take a minute to enjoy my win?
你可以
You can.
但一旦治疗时间结束  我就不接受许愿了哦
But once our time's up, I'm done granting wishes.
既然这样  我想让你告诉我
Well, in that case, I want you to tell me
你作为心理医生犯的最严重的一次错误是什么
the worst mistake you ever made as a therapist.
我们之前可没约定这个
That wasn't part of the deal.
确实没有
No, no, no, no.
你根本没和我做约定  因为你以为
You didn't make a deal with me because you were so sure
你肯定可以打败我
you were gonna beat me.
结果你没赢  所以就该愿赌服输
Well, you didn't, and it's time to pay the piper.
我不会那样做的
Well, I'm not going to do it.
看看现在是谁在逃避了
Look who's deflecting now.
我明白  好吗
Look, I get it, okay?
你来是因为你的恐惧影响到了你的工作
You're here because your fears are affecting your work,
然后现在你想要知道一次我的工作失败经历
and now you're trying to find a time where I failed at my job
这样你就能拿我撒气了
so that you can lash out at me.
我是不会让你那样做的
And I'm not gonna let you do it.
不  我只是想让你体会到
No, I just want you to know
我在这里和你说话的感受
what it feels like to be me in here with you,
如果你不愿意这样做
and if you're not willing to do that,
那你到底还有什么用
then what the hell good are you?
我害死了一个人
I killed someone.
什么
What?
我经常作为专家证人
I do a lot of work as an expert witness
为他人的心智状态做鉴定
in corporate competency situations.
-你是说滥用药物  -是的
- You mean substance abuse? - Yes.
一般这种事都是上位者
And usually it's high-powered people
想保住自己的职位
looking to keep their jobs.
但这次不一样
But this time it was different.
一个客户需要人把他儿子从戒毒所弄出来
A client needed someone to get his son out of rehab
好让他去参加他妈妈的葬礼
so that he could attend his mother's funeral.
我知道牵扯其中已经很不对
I knew it was a mistake to even get involved
因为他愿望太强烈了  而且又是长期客户
because he wanted it so badly, but he was a long-time client
而我很关心他  所以就做了
and I cared about him, so I did it.
我给他儿子做了评估
I evaluated his son.
我知道  内心深处知道他还没准备好
And I knew--I knew deep down inside he wasn't ready,
但依然给他放行了
but I gave the go-ahead anyway,
就在葬礼当晚
and the night of the funeral,
他吸毒过量致死
he overdosed and died.
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
我不希望你感到遗憾
Well, I don't want you to be sorry.
我希望你好好坐下来  跟我说实话
I want you to sit your ass down and tell me the truth
讲出你的梦
about the dream.
我跟你说过  我说的是实话
I told you before. I'm telling you the truth.
我不知道那女人是谁
I don't know who this woman was.
我刚刚跟你打开心扉
You know what, I just opened myself up to you
让你看到我理解你的感觉
to show you that I know what it's like to be you,
可其实我不理解
but I don't.
因为我知道跟自己的内心和谐相处的唯一办法
Because I know that the only way to come to terms
就是把心事说出来
with what's inside is to let it out.
而在你明白这一点之前
And until you figure that out,
你不如还是走吧
you might as well get the hell out
因为你在浪费我俩的时间
because you're wasting both our time.
我记得你以前骑自行车
I remember when you used to ride a bike.
我记得你以前是个卑鄙小人
I remember when you used to be a scumbag
但不会假装自己不是
but you didn't pretend you weren't.
叫我来这儿干嘛  坦纳
Why am I here, Tanner?
我希望你重新考虑我们的和解提议
I want you to reconsider our settlement offer.
你怎么会觉得
And what makes you think
我们愿意接受
we're going to accept the same deal
你们之前开的条件的
that you brought us before?
因为我曾跟你面对面坐着
Because I've sat across from you,
我知道你有比单纯争斗更关心的事
and I know that you care about more than just the fight.
抱歉  但是我们的争斗
Well, I'm sorry, but that fight's gonna end
会以阿丽莎・兰入狱为结束
with Alyssa Lang going to prison.
是  但不必是这样
Yeah, but it doesn't have to.
唯一要那样结束的理由
And the only reason it's gonna end that way
是因为条件是我开的
is because that deal is coming from me.
我要怎么相信你说的话呢
How the hell am I supposed to believe a word you say?
你想让我说什么
What do you want me to say, huh?
说我受够扮演坏人了吗
That I got tired of playing the goon?
我确实受够了
Because I did.
我某天早晨醒来  跟自己说
Yeah, I woke up one morning and I said,
"到此为止了"
"Enough is enough."
那之后我没有接过一件我不相信的案子
And I haven't taken one case that I don't believe in
也没做过一件自己不能接受的事
or done anything that I couldn't stomach since.
听我说  迈克
Look, mike.
我没有别的证据支持了
I don't have a leg to stand on.
也没有其他办法  但你可以说服哈维
I don't have another move, but you can convince Harvey
让他说服彼得罗夫不要毁掉这姑娘的人生
to convince Petroff not to destroy this girl's life.
你只需要觉得你是不是愿意那样
You just need to decide if you're willing to do that, man.
特拉维斯  你一直说哈维不愿意接受和解
Travis, you keep saying that Harvey won't take the deal
是因为有你在
because your name's on it.
可如果你真的改变了
But if you really are a changed man,
也许这是你证明这点的时候了
maybe it's time you prove it.
你可不是墨粉盒
Oh. Hey, you're not toner.
唐娜  拜托  别理我
Donna, please, leave me alone.
路易  你不能一辈子躲在这里
Louis, you can't hide in here forever.
我必须躲  因为我跟哈维保证过
I have to because I made a promise to Harvey,
可我不仅出了错  还把事情搞得一塌糊涂
and not only did I drop the ball, I shit the bed.
而在那之后  我还跟杰西卡说谎
And on top of that, I lied to Jessica telling her
说我不会再帮杰克玩任何阴谋
that I wouldn't be doing any more underhanded shit with Jack.
她知道你做了什么
Well, she knows what you did.
现在该去直面后果了
And it's time to face the music.
你没听我说吗
Oh, did you not just hear me?
我违抗了直接命令
I defied a direct order.
我承认那个  还不如跟她说
I admit that, I might as well tell her
一开始就是我
that I put Harvey's salary in the copy machine
把哈维的薪资单放在复印机里的
in the first place.
也许你应该说
You know what, maybe you should.
太搞笑了  你疯了吗
That's really hilarious. What, are you crazy?
不  路易  我没疯
No, Louis, I'm not.
你做了一个接一个的错误决定
You keep making bad decision after bad decision.
而这是你清除它们的机会
And this is a chance to wipe them all clean.
这没法清除任何东西
It's not gonna wipe anything clean.
只能让我被炒掉
All it's gonna do is get me fired.
是  也许会
Yeah, maybe it will.
但我知道你已经失去杰西卡的信任了
The one thing I do know is you've lost Jessica's trust.
这样做至少给了你一个机会争取回来
This at least gives you a chance to get it back.
那比缩在这里可好多了
It's a hell of a lot better than cowering in here.
怎么了  路易
What is it, Louis?
我来跟你说真相的
I'm here to tell you the truth.
说你之前说不会再帮杰克玩阴谋
That you lied when you said you weren't going
是在说谎吗
to do anything underhanded with Jack?
是我把哈维的薪资单
That I was the one that left Harvey's salary
放在复印机里的  故意的
in the copy machine... on purpose.
你为什么不说话
Why aren't you saying anything?
因为我还没决定好要怎么做
Because I haven't decided what I'm going to do.
但你要做的是...
But what you're going to do...
叫该死的杰克・索罗夫上来
is get Jack goddamn Soloff up here.
-你想见我  -是的
- You wanted to see me? - Yes, I did.
路易跟我说了点事
Louis has brought something to my attention.
什么事
And what is that?
根据律所章程C35节
Well, according to subsection C35 of the bylaws,
我们修改薪酬计算方法时
we broke protocol when we changed
违规了
the compensation formula.
胡说  根本没什么C35节
Bullshit. There is no subsection C35.
你错了
You're wrong.
-在这儿  你自己看  -我不用看
- Here, take a look. - I don't need to look.
如果你是在要求我把这话说给合伙人们
And if you're asking me to sell this to the partners,
那你运气不太好  我不会同意的
You're shit out of luck.
不  是你运气不太好
No, you're shit out of luck.
因为路易不仅拿了律所章程给我看
Because Louis didn't just come to me with the bylaws.
还承认了就是你
He admitted that it was you
故意把哈维的薪资单传出去
who deliberately put Harvey's salary out there
让所有人看到的
for all the world to see.
对吧  路易
Isn't that right, Louis?
对...不起  杰克
I...am sorry, Jack.
我必须得说实话
I had to come clean.
-那才是对的事  -你这个谎话连篇的家伙
- It was the right thing to do. - You lying piece of shit.
注意点  杰克
Watch it, Jack.
你是在跟冠名合伙人说话呢
You're talking to a name partner.
而且你说他说谎
And you're saying that he's lying,
但作为薪金委员会的领导
but as head of the compensation committee,
你完全可以查哈维的薪金
you had access to Harvey's salary.
不是我泄露的那份文件  我可以证明
I didn't leave that document out and I can prove it.
-怎么证明  -我知道的真实情况是...
- How is that? - I know for a fact that--
我来帮你说吧
Oh, let me help you out.
你之所以住口
The reason you stopped yourself
是因为你本打算说是路易泄露的
is that you were going to say Louis left it out.
但如果你早就知道  却没有提出来
But if you knew that, and still didn't come forward,
那我也可以因此而开了你
then I can fire your ass for that, too.
但你不会那样做
But you're not going to do that
因为这样你也得炒了他
because you'd also have to fire him.
可你经不起再搞一次人事变动了
And you can't afford another shake-up.
你说得对  我经不起了
You're right. I can't.
但我不在乎  因为我宁愿炒了你俩
But I don't care, because I'd rather fire you both
也不想让你摆布我
than to let you push me around.
这取决于你  杰克
So it's up to you, Jack.
要么支持C35条款
Stand by provision C35...
要么就滚蛋
or pack up your shit.
原谅我  杰西卡  你说得对
Forgive me, Jessica, you're right.
下次我会更仔细地阅读公司章程
Next time I'll read the bylaws more carefully.
从一开始  你就知道
You knew this whole thing would play out this way
结果会这样  对吗
the second it started, right?
我很清楚
I had a pretty good idea.
杰西卡...
Jessica...
我什么时候才能明白不能违背你
When am I gonna learn not to defy you?
你永远不会明白的
You're never going to learn.
但只要我清楚那点  我们就没事
But as long as I know that, we'll be okay.
我...
I--
今晚想去泥浴吗
Feel like going mudding tonight?
-不想  -我猜到了
- No. - I figured.
你最好是来告诉我  坦纳放弃了
You better be here to tell me Tanner's walking away.
我是来告诉你  我今天跟他见面了
I'm here to tell you that I met with him today.
你没告诉我就去见他了吗
You went to see him without telling me?
-我给你留了两条信息  -那又怎么样
- I left you two messages. - So the hell what?
我的案子你不能背着我去偷偷见人
You don't cut me out of a meeting on my case.
你的案子
Your case?
坦纳为你的案子提出了一个和解协议
Well, Tanner's made a settlement offer on your case,
我觉得我们应该接受
and I think that we should take it.
你开玩笑吗  我们捏着他的命门呢
Are you kidding? We have a boot to his throat.
我们没必要和解
We don't have to settle.
我们只要决定要用多大力气捏就行了
All we have to do is decide how hard to press.
你捏的不是他的命门
You're not pressing on his throat,
而是阿丽莎・兰的命门
you're pressing on Alyssa Lang's.
所以他只需要大声说他已经变了
So all he has to do is claim that he's a changed man
你就会背弃我去支持他吗
and you take his side over mine?
我没有支持他
I'm not on his side.
我们的客户不费吹灰之力就能借这个创意
Our client stands to make a fortune from this deal
-赚一大笔钱  -我才不管
- without lifting a finger. - I don't give a shit.
你看到他做了什么  也听到他是怎么说的
You saw what he did, and you heard what he said.
我们接手这件案子时
And you said when we started this,
你就说这又会像以前一样  但现在
it would be just like old times, but right now,
表现得像坏人的是你  而不是他
you're acting like the bad guy, not him.
那个烂人根本没变
That piece of shit hasn't changed
我不会跟他和解的
and I'm not settling with him.
我不是让你跟他和解
And I'm not asking you to.
这是什么
What the hell is that?
是原始协议
It's the original offer.
只是现在的律师是卡特里娜・班尼特
Only now the attorney of record is Katrina Bennet.
我让坦纳放弃这个案子
I had Tanner remove himself from the case,
现在你不是跟他和解
so now you're not settling with him.
而只是做了对大家都好的事情
You're just doing what's best for everyone.
接受协议
Take the deal.
你真的不想先读一读吗
You sure you don't want to read it first?
没这个必要
I don't have to.
泥浴俱乐部  晚十点
唐娜
瑞秋  我现在没空聊
Rachel, I cannot talk right now.
我要跟唐娜泥浴去了
I'm going mudding with Donna.
不  路易  你是要和我们俩一起去泥浴
No, Louis, you're going mudding with both of us.
路易
Louis?
我必须承认
I have to say,
我很意外你又预约来了
I'm surprised you called for another appointment.
还能说什么呢
What can I say?
你给我讲的那个故事打动了我
You telling me that story got to me.
所以你准备好说实话了吗
So you're ready to tell the truth?
准备好了
I am.
出现在我梦中的女人是唐娜
The woman in my dream was Donna.
我很高兴你回来跟我说这件事
Well, I'm glad you came back to talk about it.
既然你已对我敞开了心扉
And since you've opened up to me,
我也会对你敞开心扉
I'm going to open up to you.
我相信你说的是实话
I believe you're telling the truth.
-这就是敞开心扉吗  -不  这个才是
- That's opening up? - No, this is.
我相信你说的是实话
I believe you're telling the truth,
但我觉得你梦中的女人
But I don't think the woman
其实并不是唐娜
in your dream was actually Donna.
我觉得是你母亲
I think it was your mother.
真是难以相信
I don't believe it.
我把困扰了我好几天的事情告诉了你
I tell you the thing that's been eating at me for days,
你却说我撒谎吗
and you're calling me a liar?
不  我不是说你撒谎
No, I'm not calling you a liar.
你的梦是一系列未决问题的结合重演
Your dream was a representation of unresolved issues.
唯一的未决问题是我向你吐露心声
The only unresolved issue is I opened up
你却来激怒我
and you're turning on me.
哈维  提你母亲不是攻击你
Harvey, bringing up your mother isn't turning on you.
你完全不了解提我母亲对我意味着什么
You have no idea what bringing up my mother is to me!
我不了解  但那正是我们现在所做一切的意义
No, I don't. That's the whole point of what we're doing here.
我们现在做什么都不重要了  因为我们结束了
It doesn't matter what we're doing here 'cause we're done.
哈维  哈维
Harvey, Harvey, look.
我不在乎你挣多少钱
I don't care how much money you make
睡过多少女人
or how many women you sleep with.
你生命中有一些问题会导致你
You have issues in your life that will keep you
难以获得真正的爱情
from having real relationships.
你尽可以跟自己说
And you can tell yourself all you want
这一切与你的母亲毫无干系
that it has nothing to do with your mother,
但那是自欺欺人  你自己也清楚
but it's a lie and you know it.
我说过了  我们结束了
Well, like I said, we're done.